<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://babykaban.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://babykaban.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-25T22:13:44+00:00</updated><id>https://babykaban.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spellweaver Saga</title><subtitle>Spellweaver Saga: Retrieving The Legendary Relic is an indie game developed by babykaban. Set in the Middle Ages, it features a world filled with magic and mysterious creatures. In this game, you play as a young mage who learns to utilize elemental magic to complete quests, solve puzzles, and fight creatures in the quest to find the mysterious artifact his mentor was searching for. The game also offers rich world exploration, allowing you to uncover hidden secrets, and immerse yourself in a captivating medieval fantasy environment. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Spellweaver Saga Blog!</title><link href="https://babykaban.github.io/blog/2024/welcome-to-the-spellweaver-saga-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Spellweaver Saga Blog!"/><published>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://babykaban.github.io/blog/2024/welcome-to-the-spellweaver-saga-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://babykaban.github.io/blog/2024/welcome-to-the-spellweaver-saga-blog/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone,</p> <p>Welcome to the very first blog post for Spellweaver Saga: Retrieving The Legendary Relic! I’m Paul, the developer behind this indie game, and I’m excited to share my journey with you as I work on bringing this project to life.</p> <h1 id="game-concept">Game Concept</h1> <p>The main concept of Spellweaver Saga revolves around the player’s ability to manipulate magic elements and combine them into spells or perform actions. This mechanic is central to the entire gameplay experience. The story follows a young mage who embarks on a quest to find a powerful artifact to protect his village. This artifact was researched by his mentor, who mysteriously disappeared.</p> <h1 id="development-journey">Development Journey</h1> <p>This game is being developed on a custom engine written in C/C++. I chose to develop my own engine to deepen my understanding of programming. Although the engine is still a work in progress, I decided to proceed with creating a game to test its capabilities. After completing a prototype and evaluating the engine’s abilities, I began designing and developing the game. There were many challenges along the way, especially since I was new to game and engine development.</p> <h1 id="challenges-and-solutions">Challenges and Solutions</h1> <p>One of the most significant challenges was the overall development process. I was able to overcome many hurdles thanks to the guidance provided by the video series Handmade Hero by Casey Muratori and other internet sources. These resources have been invaluable in helping me understand game development on a deeper level.</p> <h1 id="prototype-features">Prototype Features</h1> <p>The current prototype includes a basic map layout, a few quests, and the core mechanic of combining elements. This mechanic will be significantly improved in the next version of the game. Over the last few months, I have also been working on the game’s editor, which is a crucial part of the development process. The editor currently has the capability to create custom asset files for the game.</p> <h1 id="next-steps">Next Steps</h1> <p>The next steps in the development process include finishing the editor and starting on the first levels and designs of the game. I am excited to continue this journey and share updates with you as the game progresses.</p> <h1 id="community-and-feedback">Community and Feedback</h1> <p>You can find the game prototype on the <a href="/projects/">projects page</a> or watch a demo <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7211-m05OSI">here</a>. I would love to hear your feedback and thoughts as I continue to develop Spellweaver Saga. Your input will be invaluable in shaping the final game.</p> <p>Thank you for joining me on this journey. Stay tuned for more updates and insights into the development process of Spellweaver Saga: Retrieving The Legendary Relic.</p> <p>Best, Paul</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Very First Blog Post]]></summary></entry></feed>